season seven of hermitcraft
is officially
coming to an end and as you have
probably already seen it's quite a long
video we have an awful lot to get
through an awful lot of nostalgia to
experience
and lots of things that i want to do
before i can finally call this season
done and dusted
now number one is the mansion now i've
been giving this a great deal of thought
and there's something that i would like
to discuss i've pretty much had enough
of building the mansion and while it's
not 100 complete
it's good enough and if it's good enough
for me then it should be good enough for
everyone else projects on minecraft
don't always need to be 100 finish in
fact i don't think i've ever completed a
proper project
entirely to 100 perfection it's just not
how minecraft works sometimes 80 is
perfect
and regarding the why is there tnt on
the cake now that is weird
and i'm gonna leave it there but
regarding the back of the mansion you
know it's been such a meme at this point
that it doesn't actually feel right to
finish it now i know that scar
was supposed to do it for losing the
turf wall but you know what it's the end
of the season i'm feeling pretty
generous i'm not gonna hold him to that
if he doesn't want to finish it i don't
blame him because
i certainly don't
so this is how we're gonna leave the
mansion there is one thing that i does
really bother me i know there's multiple
things about this mansion that aren't
done like this
but for some reason there's one thing
that really annoys me and it's the fact
that there's no trees on this side
literally that that side has some trees
they're not great but this side doesn't
it's just been bone milled and it looks
kind of rubbish
so what i want to do very quickly is
just the final touches and i'm gonna
call this finished
well as finished as i want to make it
there we go it's absolutely nothing
special but it was bothering me quite a
lot so we've now got pretty much as far
as we're gonna get with the mansion and
before you get all disappointed i don't
think i've ever completed you know
season six i didn't complete my build it
was done on the outside but the inside
was definitely not so i'm just keeping
up with tradition this is
more than enough for me i am extremely
proud of what has been created here over
the last year and a bit and i've kept
every single bit of time-lapse footage
and guess what this project
over 200 hours
you could say
it was a lot of work
[Music]
work
work all day
[Music]
here is
all day
[Music]
well there we have it the full
experience the full time lapse probably
went a little bit too fast for comfort
but there was literally so much footage
i couldn't fit it all in the one minute
30 length of that song
so that was absolutely
incredible and that kind of covers
the green mansion from this season now
there's a something that i saw in the
comments that i apparently have to do
for the last episode and it's this i
need to do another
jungle map but here's the thing
i'm fairly sure
that there's not a lot of difference
between episode 73
and 76. maybe ren has done a little bit
more work but honestly
it looks pretty identical to this maybe
there's like a little bit of difference
here but honestly
it's pretty much identical but i can do
it it just seems wrong to have three
three episodes difference between maps
now going back in time there's something
that i want to do and it involves
something from the very start of the
season this here messaging system now i
need to send mumbo jumbo
one last message it's been a long time
since i've sent mumbo a message and the
message reads
well i didn't miss that
i forgot about that bit
so the message reads shall we go and
visit our son
i would like to visit grumbot one last
time but i'm not gonna do it without
mumbo now one of the other things that's
been worked on quite extensively in
hermitcraft is
among us in hermitcraft now this is a
project that tango has done now tango
has done an awful lot of work on this
and we all got together a few days ago
to play a few rounds so that's where
we're gonna go now now i'm not gonna
include all of it because it's hours
long but here is my favorite round from
that session of among us it was a lot of
fun to play and thank you very much
tango for inviting me to do so
dubs
there's only three tasks we can speed
run this yep we can do this all right
clean the books yeah
rub it in there
chicken feed chicken feet chicken feed
let's go
go go go go go go go go go go go
oh no here comes here wait wait wait
see if i can get there in time
oh i thought everyone else had gone
weird weird why is green over here oh i
i just yeah see everyone else is gone
wait how
do you have to
how does this work
do you just have to spam them
spam spam
spam
how does this oh you're alive
i have no idea do you do you just spam
it
where's tango i'm gonna ask him about
that i've only got that i've only got
the lightificator left and i can't seem
to get it to work
do you know b-dubs
what get what
[Laughter]
seriously
stop it
you stop it stop seriously close the
doors
close the doors no seriously
what no i've got one task left and it
doesn't seem to work
what task is that the crossbow
do it
hey hey hey
[Music]
quickly
i missed the glasses
oh
where's the purple man guys where's the
purple man
i was shocked
sorry i'm dead i'm dead i'm i'm
misclicked i'm dead okay
okay bye girl shot me and missed oh wow
i'm a perfect shot i would never miss
and i was chasing when did you call this
green just now i called the meeting with
my token because we both ran to the
thing he got there first
hey
cause i all right i've been suss on
green because the first reactor he was
running away from it yeah well i figured
if everyone else tried to go and deliver
my chain
thank you yeah you helped me with the
seeds i spilled the seeds i'm so hungry
in here yes green has also been having
trouble on a task apparently yeah he
didn't go back to it no i finished it i
finished my tasks it was the light the
last one i had to do is the
lightificator after doing the change
powerful it is
no no no honestly
oh
i'm throwing scott honestly when a
british person says honestly they're
lying by the way there's a race to the
it was a race to the button because he
missed
yeah no it's true it's true i always say
that you know you're dead don't let me
back in there with the murderer he tried
to kill me once he's going to kill me
again i need somebody to be a buddy
when he kills you you're just going to
be really sad everyone
all right where's the chicken coop tank
what do you think
i'm not i'm confused man i'm doing my
car
i saw you trying to get to the you all
are the worst
i am done with my attempted murder oh
that was great
things
[Laughter]
[Music]
scott
i can't believe you just did that
who the heck did it both
i can't believe this
why would you do such a thing
right right vote for scar oh my god you
said you better did everyone vote for
grant all right i'm going to go this way
it'll be clear that we're before
discussion here voting orange we're
voting orange here
running purple we're voting here right
correct and i would do it again just
came out of
[Laughter]
i'd do it again
among us was an awful lot of fun and
although it was a little bit clunky it
was a marvelous piece of redstone i
could never imagine how difficult that
was to make
but there is someone else on the server
that has been creating
tons and tons of content and mini games
that i have not actually been able
to give a go
so what i'm going to do now is head over
to cub fans base where he's created
target
now cubs base is one of the most
impressive excessive builds that i've
seen in a long time it is enormous
and inside
cub has gone and made a thing called
tarjay which consists of a bunch of
minigames so i'm gonna message cub and
see if he'll give me a little bit of a
1v1 and we'll play some of his favorite
minigames from his base
because i i haven't played any of them
and it's kind of embarrassing so
let's see if we can meet up with cub and
play some games
green a very warm welcome to target
target i've been i can't believe it's
been this long i've i've been here once
or twice and i've wanted to play some
games but i'm glad i finally maybe the
like my last episode but i'm i'm glad to
be here this is super fun what are we
playing yeah yeah yeah we're playing
dunk tank are you uh are you a dunker
are you a basketball player you can dunk
on 10 feet right
no
no okay okay well good thing we're not
playing basketball then so
all right and then basically what we do
we bounce snowballs off of bubble
columns try and hit the targets first
person to do that
okay
yeah just like that oh that's so sweet
okay all right let's do let's do best of
three okay we'll count down three two
one and go okay here we go
three two one go
oh
no no no yes
dunk
[Music]
oh
not quite the deciding round
you're up you're up by one still you're
up by one okay
ready to go two
one go
inside the duck
come on get up get the corner get the
corner come on come on i get this one
don't you worry
it's going too fast
i think i think you got me just before
just before that is that the closest
game of dunk master ever
i think it might it was must've been
close that was three to two
done well done oh that's brilliant cub
that is an excellent game
all right so this one is whack-a-mole
this one is whack-a-mole uh yeah you
have to whack the targets with your
arrows
and uh that's basically it that's
basically it okay
uh let me get a blowout
okay there's two modes in this one
so the way the way you play is you press
the button to start you shoot your
targets you get points uh first to nine
wins right three two
one
oh oh they come up randomly they come up
randomly
you gotta be quick yep you gotta be
quick
okay okay i got this all right yeah this
one you kind of have to focus a little
bit yeah yeah you're telling me
it really comes up fast
it does i'm better off just guessing
oh man
this is good to practice like flick
shots yeah it really is
come on come on where is this target
oh that was fast i missed that one too
fast
come on
oh i don't know what i'm at i must be at
like six though i don't even know i
don't have time to pull back my bow
my reflexes i'm too old for this game
there it is
oh
congrats
beautiful i must i got a fair few it
must have been pretty close how good are
you at shooting my friend you got a good
i like to think that i am but i just
sucked at the whack-a-mole so
all right all right well this one this
one's only into five but it's called
bullseye because you gotta hit the
bull's-eye to score oh the like the
exact mid-point all right here we go
here we go
go oh
gotta wait for the countdown there we go
now we go now we're going
oh okay it's surprisingly difficult to
keep your bow in exactly the same spot
it is yeah there is a little bit of like
variation too oh come on there's a
little bit of chance involved
come on
there we go i'm pretty sure i'm in the
right spot
green's in the league gotta come back
well done
gg brilliant man oh amazing
well cub it's been a blast playing
through some of these games i'm sorry we
didn't get to play all of them but it
was absolutely amazing and
target i think will be
something that people enjoy in the world
download for for years to come
definitely definitely i hope so all
right well thank you very much for
showing me around and playing these
games i had a lot of fun actually yeah
cheers green anytime well that was an
awful lot of fun i did actually play a
few more games after the recording with
cub
but that was a pretty good sample and if
you get the world download definitely
check out tarjay in the enormous
toblerone right now i have had a message
from our good friend mumbo jumbo
and he says
we should meet up with our son so let's
head over to our favorite robot stuck in
the matrix grumbot back on the old end
rods yeah back on the old dogs
do you know what we haven't recorded in
like what seven months or something and
we both just naturally just went and
stood on the end rods
yeah i mean what else could we possibly
do you know this is this is the way that
we have to have conversations with one
another this is like a handshake for me
and you this is how we say hello we
group one another by just standing on
standing on the old end rods right here
we are anyway well i'm glad that you got
my message about saying goodbye to our
son it doesn't feel right to not say
goodbye at the end of the season
been a while since we've been here so um
i thought we could say goodbye together
i mean he does he seems like he's in
still in bliss he's blessed to be honest
no i did think about giving you like a
mare skin and just like
oh that's true yeah we might have like
broken the illusion you know it's it's
quite cool like he he has no idea that
the mycelium war happened like
everything was true
he's still my silly of him we built him
before that oh man yeah better not have
this conversation in front of him
oh yeah sorry we need to stop reminding
him
we just see him getting gradually across
right i'm going to rename a diamond and
i'm going to say
goodbye grumbot
we will miss you
we will miss you yeah yeah seems good do
you remember how to use this thing i
actually have no clue how to use this
thing i've completely forgotten i'm
sorry gunbot you put you put that in
there you press oh yes
oh i forgot about this prime grumbot
that's the one yeah
bootload brain
[Music]
and then you deposit the question
diamond okay cool
and then he beat for it oh no he didn't
need to think about that
he came straight out
he's
somebody's overclocked grumbot in the
time that we've been away he's just been
performing upgrades on himself
wow
you're being attacked by an invisible
he's sent out
is this is granbot's new way of saying
that he's cross
it says goodbye dads grumbot loves you
ah
that honestly it feels a little bit
strange that we're gonna switch off the
server with him still in it like if
there was some way that we could get him
out can we print him as an nft
alright then well that's it i guess uh i
guess i'll see you in season eight then
yeah i mean
and i guess uh
yeah i'll see you in season eight and
grumble i guess i will
everyone will get to enjoy grambot
because there's the the world will be
down for download and they can all go
inside and see how it works or not
figure out how it works or you'll break
the illusion how about that yeah
exactly yeah no we can just leave and be
all right nobody fiddles inside of
grandpa's brain please and we just uh
yeah we leave him to exist in his happy
bliss and no reminding him that i'm
i'm there not the mayor yeah i said that
quietly and away from him just in case
he can read lips and everything you know
all right well see you in season eight
buddy see you in season eight we will
miss you grumbot and enjoy and you shall
live on forever in the world download
now season seven has been a little bit
shorter than season six but it's still
been incredibly long
whole episodes and a lot of things
happen in that time it's been over a
year this entire series and there's been
some funny funny things that have
happened and i've compiled the best
things that have happened in a very
short
best of
so here are my absolute favorite moments
from season seven enjoy
it worked
[Laughter]
oh no scar i didn't i
didn't mean for you to die hello
hello
you see the issue is it that there's too
many of them so they just spam hello at
me let's get rid of a villager that we
don't want it's
[Music]
oh my goodness
oh my god that was so clutch i really
really wanted your mustache if you press
press f5 really quick oh no what have
you done what have you done
hang on hang on have you taken a patch
of my hair and put it on your face and i
have a patch of your hair and it's on
the no i've got a rear mustache
really
yes the sun is setting we have to
this is my service to the community
hey don't do that this is important
there's going to be things in the sky
phantoms and you'll see don't
hey you owe me some doors what
yeah let's start this yeah bendy let's
stop this let's start this building okay
all right yeah let's start to build in
the morning
okay i'm out i'm out of punch range i'm
out of punch range all right go go for
it let's go
we'll stand over here
all right have a great night's sleep
guys
i love it i love it so much it's
satisfying isn't it
are we gonna get him going
what did you say
oh i think we might have insulted his
intelligence a little bit
i think
what's he saying
yes but grumbot does not want to
is that really his response
i got my book here hit it with the flame
bow
hit it with the flame though hit it with
the flame though
how is anyone going to vote for mayor
how is anyone going to support you to be
there
oh my goodness
oh amazing
that was actually extremely successful
ah what
no no no things aren't going well
no grinding
that's okay that that's how good things
normally go
[Music]
he's made a song
genius
[Music]
not even close b he's just given up can
anyone
sleep please
okay can anyone's oh yeah he's not there
what's he doing can anyone sleep please
[Laughter]
actually did it
oh no
it's there now just down here go go go
go go go
it's down
[Music]
your command don't do it no
it's instant it's instant death it's not
even funny he's vanishing
yeah
what is going on
oh my god that scared the life out of me
i
i have something special
and it only
costs whatever you want it to cost
want to buy
pay up front
this man knows how to do business
what the heck
what um
oh no no corrales no stop
stop that was it
that was it
what do i do
he's given me two sacks of diamonds i
never want to see it again
that's right no it's real it's happening
it's going up
oh my goodness
goodbye
mansion oh no
goodbye manche oh my goodness what a
mess
oh oh no it didn't even want to load my
mansion my beautiful mansion it's so
what have you done
really it's a pesky bird
right here
okay whoa
okay this is a that was good safety
oh my goodness panic panic panic
emergency meeting oh that's including me
panic
they found us
grab
stuff
get
the mycelium
get them out
they're over there
oh my goodness
get the source block
get the source block did i get this
right that ren found the star cause i
saw him pick it up he then died to a
wither and then you picked it up and ran
in
they did all the fighting and died like
three more times but eventually got it
in the woods
watch this oh he's not gonna try it is
he
he's not going to try it
oh no
[Laughter]
it gets you in but how do we get out we
got to get back safely take two into
poles okay it's on we won what
they won
they won i guess they need to put it in
now they need to put it in front of it
oh no
oh
[Laughter]
[Music]
ice cream maui keep looking at each
other
oh my goodness
[Laughter]
in fact in fact i might just uh make
myself at home real quick
don't you dare
no you dare
i might just uh just put yeah just
oh that's better isn't it i've just i
carry all this stuff around with me for
ages and now there's more space in the
base to put all this stuff back which is
brilliant
so you know you've just gotten
it's always nice to take a trip through
memory lane now one of the last things
that i would like to do before we sign
off from this series is add my head to
mount hermit more people have been
slowly i think as they've ended their
series maybe been adding their heads
here i need to add mine
i think i'll put mine right here
i need to look at my own face now for
reference
i've made this face several times but i
can never quite remember
do my eyes go
here
no
no no they go one over
add in all the hair
there we go immortalized on mount hermit
more this is really nice i really hope
that everyone will put their face on
here although i feel sorry for the
people that do it right at the end
because it's going gonna be difficult to
squeeze everything in
so now that that is done let's head back
to the base
right let's put all our stuff away
there's one shulker box which has been
very important to me this entire season
and that is the more doors box it's got
everyone's doors that i've stolen over
the course of the season and some
people's doors like scars i've had to
name in fact i gave up on naming them
and numbering them because there was
just too many of them there's a whole
shulker box of them for you to explore
likewise i also collected people's heads
from the season i didn't end up using
most of them but they're there as well
and finally
the shiny box
these are all the diamonds that i have
got over the course of the season and
that's not even including the diamonds i
used for the chandeliers and all the
other things that i've done
so that is a huge amount of diamonds
this has been the most diamond
successful series i've ever done look at
that and you guys know
i didn't do an awful lot of mining so
what i'm going to do before i sign off
is i'm going to put my elytra
and all my armor in here with the tools
that i have left remaining to me in here
for you to enjoy
there we go all nice and labeled greens
wallet and armor hope you loved season
seven see you in season eight
now i'm not really gonna do a world tour
because i actually did one not too long
ago and i thought of a better way to see
out the series than going around and
seeing the bases although i have to say
i love what's happened in this area i
love how the proximity of being next to
everyone has really really
built this place up to be amazing wait a
minute
is that
is that what i think it is
huh
better late than never sahara diamonds
i love the fact that they're proper
stuck in mumbo's base
well at least they turned up well
that is it
for another season it's been an
absolutely brilliant ride i've learned a
lot and i've had a lot of fun
season 8 i hope will be slightly
different and bring all kinds of new
shenanigans stories and of course
more lovely builds
i'm gonna miss the mansion but it's time
for us
to say goodbye to this season
but not without
saying a proper
good
bye
[Music]
[Applause]
you